



















Raj Gawera · 2nd

VP & Managing Director of Samsung Cambridge & Samsung Denmark Research Centres

- Samsung Cambridge Solution Centre
- University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business

Greater Cambridge Area · Contact info

500+ connections



David Pardoe, Deborah Opoku, and 5 other mutual connections

Connect



More

Highlights

You both worked at Samsung Cambridge Solution Centre You both worked at Samsung Cambridge Solution Centre from January 2020 to August 2021



About

Raj has over 20 years of experience in short range and wireless comms technology R&D, bus dev and marketing. Raj was part of initial IEEE 802.11 team to define first WLAN standard in 1996 – a technology which has now shipped over 5bn units. Raj also helped pioneer the first 3G data transmissions worl ...see more

Activity

1,738 followers

Raj Gawera commented on a post • 1w

Great photo, great team!



2 comments

Raj Gawera commented on a post • 1w

Many congrats Richard. Great to see you extending your positive influence!



139 comments

7 comments

Raj Gawera commented on a post • 1w

Very thought provoking post Penny. A strong reminder to us all to continually be aware of subconscious bias and make the extra effort to strive for an inclusive and safe environment for all to flourish! Proud of you!



Show all activity →

Experience

VP & Managing Director of Samsung Cambridge and Samsung Denmark

Samsung Cambridge Solution Centre · Full-time Aug 2014 - Present · 8 yrs 10 mos Cambridge, United Kingdom

Responsible for leading several R&D offices for the System LSI division of Samsung Electronics. The R&D teams focus on wireless communication, specifically Wi-Fi and Bluetooth technologies. The IP developed by the teams has been incorporated into high volume chipset products that have been built into millions of end products such as smartphones, tablets, wearables and IOT home appliances. The multi-disciplinary team covers radio architecture/systems, digital design and architecture, signal processing algorithms, embedded firmware and system/integration test. The engineers also contribute into the IEEE802.11, WFA and BT SIG standardisation efforts.

Non Executive Director

Compound Semiconductor Applications (CSA) Catapult · Part-time Nov 2021 - Present · 1 yr 7 mos Newport, Wales, United Kingdom

I was invited to join the board of the CSAC to broaden out the experience base of the board. As the Catapult continues to evolve, winnin ... see more

Non Exec Director, Board of Directors

GGD Genex

Jan 2013 - Present · 10 yrs 5 mos Cambridge, United Kingdom

Non Exec Director on a family company set up to provide accounting and financial services to the growing community of startups in the...



CW (Cambridge Wireless Ltd)

9 yrs 2 mos

Cambridge, United Kingdom

Chair Of The Board Of Directors

Part-time

Dec 2015 - May 2022 · 6 yrs 6 mos

After joining the CW board, I was elected by my fellow board members to become the Chair of the CW board. CW is a unique organisat ...see more

Founder Member - Board Director

Apr 2013 - Dec 2015 · 2 yrs 9 mos

After a record breaking election by the Cambridge Wireless membership, I was elected to the Founder Member position on the Board o ...see more

VP Marketing/ Strategy & Planning

Samsung Cambridge Solutions Centre Jun 2012 - Aug 2014 · 2 yrs 3 mos Cambridge, United Kingdom

• Following Samsung's acquisition of CSR's Handset business, I was appointed to lead the marketing function in the newly formed ...see more

Show all 10 experiences →

Education



University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business



Aston University

Master of Engineering (MEng), Electronics Systems Engineering Grade: 1st Class

Sponsored by British Telecom

Skills